<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Notes about various things</title>
    <link>http://blog.nickto.net/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Notes about various things</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2017 20:40:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://blog.nickto.net/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Acceptance-rejection method for generating random variables</title>
      <link>http://blog.nickto.net/2017-02-10-acceptance-rejection-method-for-generating-random-variables/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2017 20:40:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.nickto.net/2017-02-10-acceptance-rejection-method-for-generating-random-variables/</guid>
      <description>Acceptance-rejection method is a method for generating samples from a distribution, for which the probability density function is known, but inverse cumulative probability function is not known, and thus, using the inverse CDF method is not possible.
Although there is quite a lot of information on the topic available, I will try to explain the method the way that I (a.k.a 5-year-old) understand.
Idea Majorizing distribution Let us say that we want to draw numbers from some distribution1 $ f(x) $&amp;mdash;target distribution&amp;mdash;but we have only distribution $ g(x) $, such that by multiplying it with some constant $ c $ it is always larger than $ f(x) $,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LaTeX fonts in R Markdown plots</title>
      <link>http://blog.nickto.net/2017-02-03-latex-fonts-in-r-markdown-plots/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2017 19:30:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.nickto.net/2017-02-03-latex-fonts-in-r-markdown-plots/</guid>
      <description>Let us be honest, one of the reasons we use R Markdown to compile documents into PDF is the aesthetic pleasure provided by LaTeX. However, all the efforts can be ruined by wrong fonts in plots that are not the same as in the rest of the document. For example
Well, these are some ugly fonts (not by itself, but in combination with the rest of the document). Would not it be much better to have something like this?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Table and figure captions in R Markdown</title>
      <link>http://blog.nickto.net/2016-11-10-table-and-figure-captions-in-r-markdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2016 15:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.nickto.net/2016-11-10-table-and-figure-captions-in-r-markdown/</guid>
      <description>R Markdown is an extremely useful tool for producing reports using R. The problem is that decent quality reports require captions for figures and tables, and it is not straightforward to do. The good news is that it is still quite easy.
Pandoc&amp;rsquo;s Markdown: numbered captions The key to adding captions is that knitr actually converts your .Rmd file to .md file first, and then uses pandoc to conert it to html, pdf or another format.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>